<NewDataSet>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac10</tag>
    <content>At minimum flood, current frequently ebbs for a short period.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac2</tag>
    <content>Current speeds up to 9.0 knots have been observed in the vicinity of the
Boilers.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac24</tag>
    <content>The times of minimum before flood and ebb are variable.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac29</tag>
    <content>Current tends to rotate clockwise.  At times for Minimum before flood there
may be a weak current flowing west southwest, while at times for Minimum
before ebb there may be a weak current flowing north.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac3</tag>
    <content>Current turns westward just before the end of the flood.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac30</tag>
    <content>Current tends to rotate clockwise.  At times for Minimum before flood there
may be a weak current flowing southwest, while at times for Minimum before
ebb there may be a weak current flowing north.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac31</tag>
    <content>Flood usually flows northward, however, direction is variable.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac33</tag>
    <content>Due to changes in the waterway, average speed values given are probably too
large.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac35</tag>
    <content>Flood is weak and variable.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac36</tag>
    <content>Current tends to rotate clockwise.  At times for Minimum before flood there
may be a weak current flowing northward while at times for Minimum before ebb
there may be weak current flowing southeastward.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac43</tag>
    <content>Minimum ebb is extremely weak, possibly flooding for a short period.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac44</tag>
    <content>Every other ebb phase exhibits a double ebb pattern.  For single ebb phase
use time differences and speed ratio of the first ebb.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac51</tag>
    <content>Observations were made during the summer months when freshwater discharge
was at a minimum.  Periods of heavier discharge will increase ebb current
speeds and decrease flood current speeds.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac52</tag>
    <content>Observations were made in the spring during periods of heavy freshwater
discharge.  Periods of lesser discharge will decrease the ebb current speeds
and increase flood current speeds.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac54</tag>
    <content>Turbulence with hazardous current speeds of 6 to 7 knots have been reported
near the bridges in the canal.  Extreme caution should be exercised.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac58</tag>
    <content>It has been reported that under conditions of extreme river discharge, the
current can reach 7 to 8 knots.  Caution should be exercised when docking and
undocking vessels.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac62</tag>
    <content>Short term observational data taken by United States Power Squadrons (USPS)
as part of the NOS/USPS Tidal Current Predictions Quality Assurance Program
has shown that predictions at this location are accurate.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac63</tag>
    <content>Short term observational data taken by United States Power Squadrons (USPS)
as part of the NOS/USPS Tidal Current Predictions Quality Assurance Program
has shown predictions at these locations to be inaccurate.  Predictions
provided should be used with caution.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac64</tag>
    <content>At times of slack before flood there is a non-tidal current flowing NE at
speeds of approximately 0.5 knots.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>ac9</tag>
    <content>At minimum flood, current sometimes ebbs for a short period.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc10</tag>
    <content>Current is somewhat rotary, turning counterclockwise.  4h 25m prior to
computed maximum flood the current flows southward with a speed 0.6 of the
flood speed at the reference station.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc105</tag>
    <content>Observations indicate the existence of a permanent current setting north
with an average speed of 0.7 knot.  Combined with the tidal current, the
northward current may have an average speed varying from slack to 1.4 knots.
The greatest observed speed off Maui Island was 2.7 knots.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc121</tag>
    <content>Due to disturbances caused by the structure, observed currents within 50
feet of the pier can be significantly different from the predictions.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc13</tag>
    <content>Data approximate.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc21</tag>
    <content>Current is rotary, turning clockwise.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc27</tag>
    <content>Flood speed at strength probably does not become less than a knot.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc33</tag>
    <content>Close to the east shore the flood speed is reduced about 1/2 but the ebb
speed is only slightly less than at Point Evans.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc34</tag>
    <content>On the west side the speed of the flood current is 0.6 that of midstream and
the ebb begins about 1 hour and 15 minutes earlier.  On the east side the
current is about the same as midstream.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc41</tag>
    <content>Ebb current is irregular at times.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc45</tag>
    <content>Dangerous eddy current and tide rips are reported to occur between Helmcken
Island and Ripple Shoal around the time of ebb strength.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc46</tag>
    <content>On the flood, the streams coming from the sea through the north and south
entrances meet off Evening Point (Lat 53 39N) and separate on the falling
tide about a mile farther northward.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc59</tag>
    <content>Northeast of Lively Island, it is reported that the current sets constantly
northwestwards, being stronger when the main stream west of the island sets
northwestwards.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc62</tag>
    <content>Current frequently ebbs throughout the day, especially when moon is in
quadrature.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc63</tag>
    <content>Slacks before flood may be variable.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc66</tag>
    <content>The currents in Nawasina Passage, except at the location 1 1/2 miles west of
Allan Point, are too weak and variable to be predicted.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc85</tag>
    <content>Ratios are for greater flood and greater ebb only.  The flood and ebb
inequalities are small when the moon is near the equator.  At other times
there is considerable difference between the two floods and also the two ebbs
in a day.  The lesser flood may even become a small ebb at extreme
declinations.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc9</tag>
    <content>Current is somewhat rotary, turning counterclockwise.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc93</tag>
    <content>Current is somewhat rotary turning clockwise.  At times given for slack,
flood begins and slack, ebb begins the current probably flows WNW and ESE
respectively, with speed of about 1.5 knots.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc94</tag>
    <content>The current changes from ebb to flood abruptly and predictions for beginning
of flood are approximate.</content>
  </Table>
  <Table>
    <tag>pc96</tag>
    <content>Current is rotary turning clockwise.  At the predicted times of slack before
flood or ebb the current will run westward or eastward respectively with
speed about 0.2 knot.</content>
  </Table>
</NewDataSet>